从很久以前开始
In Sixteen Hundred Seven
航海是我本事
We sailed the open sea
荣耀尊贵财富全靠
For glory, God and gold
维吉尼亚大公司
And the Virginia Company
新的世界就像天堂
For the New World is like heaven
我们大家都向往
And we'll all be rich and free
要消息灵通全靠这
Or so we have been told
维吉尼亚大公司
By the Virginia Company
消息灵通全靠这
So we have been told
维吉尼亚大公司
By the Virginia Company
荣耀尊贵财富全靠
For glory, God, and gold
维吉尼亚大公司
And the Virginia Company
-  准备好吊起大跑了吗？ -  准备好了！
- Ready to hoist the cannon? - Aye!
你看  那是庄迈斯吗？
Hey, look. Is that Smith?
是他  没错  老练的水手
That's him, all right. The old sea dog.
庄迈斯上尉 我听说过不少他的传奇
Captain John Smith? I've heard amazing stories about him.
你要跟我们一块去远航吗？
Are you coming on this voyage, too?
当然了  那还用说吗？ 打印第安鬼哪能没有他啊
Course he is, you half-wit! You can't fight Indians without John Smith!
就是嘛 这种场面怎么能丢下我呢
That's right. I'm not about to let you boys have all the fun.
我们靠岸的那地方
On the beaches of Virginny
满地都是宝藏
There's diamonds like debris
它遍地黄金
There's silver rivers flowin'
不用愁口袋会响叮
Gold you pick right off a tree
这金块给我的爱人
With a nugget for my Winnie
这一块给我自己
And another one for me
其它所得通通交给
And all the rest'll go
维吉尼亚大公司
To the Virginia Company
荣耀尊贵财富全靠
It's glory, God, and gold
维吉尼亚大公司
And the Virginia Company
抓紧缆绳
Full anchor release!
小心  小心
Come on, lads! Come on!
抓紧缆绳
Give me a hand, someone!
用力
Watch out!
快受不了这个暴雨
Faster! She's taking on more water!
小心
Look out!
迈斯  快下来呀
John! Get down here!
这门跑快散掉了
The cannons are breaking loose!
-抓方向盘！ -是的  大人！
- Reef the topsails! - Aye, sir!
大家不要慌！
Steady on your course!
镇定点  汤姆斯 先把船稳住
It's all right, Thomas! We'll get her tied off.
大伙  祈祷吧
Say your prayers, lads!
小心！
Look out!
汤姆斯  小心！
Thomas, watch out...!
救命啊！
Help!
有人落海了
Man overboard!
救命啊！
Help!
别下去  他死定了
Stay your course! He's lost!
救命啊！
Help!
拽绳子 遵命  大人！
- Pull the pin. - Aye, sir!
迈斯
Smith!
你疯了你
Are you crazy?
撑下去  汤姆斯  我帮你
Hang on, Thomas. I've got you!
快  绳子！
Quick... the rope!
拉起来
Heave!
伙伴们  拉啊
Come on, lads! Pull!
拉  用力拉
Pull! Pull!
大伙用全力
Put your back into it!
拉…
Pull! Pull!
坚持住
Hang on!
好  把他救回来了
Ah, my lucky lad!
真够呛
Well, that was refreshing.
多亏有你呀  迈斯 哪里
- Well done, Smith. - Of course...
是大伙一起出力的
...you'd all do the same for me.
是  是 就是嘛
- Yes, yes. - Sure, sure.
-我们都出力了  ！ -对  我们都出力了
- Of course we would! Absolutely! - Yeah, we would.
出事了吗？
Trouble on deck?
雷利夫总督大人 汤姆斯掉进海里了
- Governor Ratcliffe! - Thomas fell overboard, sir.
能把他救回来 真是感谢上帝
Thank heavens he's been successfully retrieved.
记你一功  迈斯 谢谢  大人
- Well done, Smith. - Thank you, sir.
别再大意了 不多久我们就到达新大陆
Don't lose heart, men. It won't be long before we reach the New World,
知道什么在等着我们吗？
and remember what awaits us there...
自由  锦绣前程 多彩多姿的生活
Freedom, prosperity, the adventure of our lives.
你们全都是来自英国 最优秀的队员
You're the finest crew England has to offer,
无论什么  不管是风是雨
and nothing, not wind nor rain,
还是上千万个蛮夷部族 都要勇往直前
nor a thousand bloodthirsty savages shall stand in our way.
坚持下去
Carry on, men!
真是振奋人心啊  大人
A stirring oration, sir.
现在大伙热血沸腾
I'm sure the men were most exhilarated!
但愿如此  我还得靠这些 愚蠢的人帮我挖金子呢  对吧？
Let us hope so. I'll need those witless peasants to dig up my gold, won't I?
哇  这新大陆可真不赖  迈斯
This New World's going to be great, John.
让我捧着大量黄金
I'm going to get a pile of gold,
回家盖大楼  要是蛮夷他们 敢来捣乱的话  我就给他一枪
build me a big house, and if any Indian tries to stop me, I'll blast him.
你尽管去照顾你的黄金 汤姆斯
Just worry about that fortune of yours, Thomas.
蛮夷交给我就行了 你是说蛮夷很难对付？
- Leave the savages to me. - You think they'll give us trouble?
庄迈斯会让他们吃苦头
Not as much trouble as Smith'll give them.
来一个我们就杀一个
We'll kill ourselves an injun
来两个…
Or maybe two or three
我忠心耿耿属於这 维吉尼亚大公司
We're stalwart men and bold ofthe Virginia Company
你觉得新大陆会是什么样子的呢？
What do you suppose the New World will look like?
我觉得跟其他地方没什么两样
Like all the others, I suppose.
新大陆我以前见过不少了 汤姆斯
I've seen hundreds of New Worlds, Thomas.
这个又能有什么不同？
What could possibly be different about this one?
荣耀尊贵财富全靠
It's glory
维吉尼亚大公司
God, and gold
And the Virginia Company
「风中奇缘」
打着鼓来敲着钟
Steady as the beating drum
歌唱不停庆丰收
Singing to the cedar flute
春去秋来冬又过
Seasons go and seasons come
收获载满一篓筐
Bring the corn and bear the fruit
靠着河边水又清
By the waters sweet and clean
万物一起来和应
Where the mighty sturgeon lives
食物水果洒满地
Plant the squash and reap the bean
天生天养乐无比
All the earth our Mother gives
悠哉悠哉歌声中
O, Great Spirit, hear our song
天生天养乐无比
Help us keep the ancient ways
围着火来胆更壮
Keep the sacred fires strong
日子一天又一天
Walk in balance all our days
春去秋来冬又过
Seasons go and seasons come
打着鼓来敲着钟
Steady as the beating drum
每当收获不放弃
Plum to seed to bud to plum
打着鼓来敲着钟
Steady as the beating drum
包华顿 纪克泰
回到家来真好
It's good to be home.
木索乌美族被打败了
The Massawomecks are defeated!
靠兄弟们同心协力 我们的部族又太平了
With the help of our brothers, our villages are safe again.
看你胜利归来令族人多兴奋哪
Your return has brought much joy to the village.
他们都笑得多开心
Look at all the smiling faces.
是啊！不过好像还少了一个人
Yes. But there's one smiling face I don't see.
我女儿呢？
Where is my daughter?
你是说宝嘉康蒂啊
You know Pocahontas.
她有她母亲的遗传
She has her mother's spirit.
永远随着风向到处跑
She goes wherever the wind takes her.
宝嘉康蒂！
Pocahontas!
你爸爸回来了
Your father's back.
快下来
Come down here!
爸回来了  菲莉
He's back, Flit.
走吧  米糕
Come on, Meeko!
不  又来了
No! Not that... way.
爱现
Show-off.
宝嘉康蒂？
Pocahontas?
宝嘉康蒂？你没事吧？
Pocahontas? Are you all right?
你不要再装神弄鬼了 我可不会跟你跳到水里去的
You'd better be all right, because I'm not coming in after you...
就爱玩这种花样 你以为我们还小啊？
Don't you think we're getting a little old for these games?
帮忙翻过来
Help me turn this thing over.
你刚刚在上面干什么？
What were you doing up there?
思考啊  米糕
Thinking. Meeko!
又在想那个梦啊 那你又想到什么呢？
About the dream again? Have you figured it out yet?
其中一定有什么含意 我就是搞不懂
I know it means something, I just don't know what.
你应该去问问你爸爸 说得也是
- You should ask your father about it. - Maybe I should.
来吧  菲莉
Come on, Flit.
不要再疯了  我们该走了
Quit playing around. We have to get back.
就跟敌人决一死战
...faced a determined enemy.
那场仗打从太阳升起开始
The battle lasted from the rising of the sun
一直激战到夜幕低垂
until the evening shadows fell.
勇士们都奋勇杀敌 可就数高刚最英勇
Our warriors fought with courage, but none as bravely as Kocoum,
他就像猛虎出闸 所向匹敌
for he attacked with the fierce strength of the bear.
-他智勇双全  证明他是… -你看  高刚真的好帅哦
- He has proven himself to be... - He is so handsome!
他的笑容才迷人呢
I especially love the smile.
把敌人彻底歼灭
...destroying every enemy in his path.
今晚我们要为他庆祝
Tonight, we will feast in his honor.
乖女儿 爸
- My daughter. - Winggapo, Father.
看到你我就高兴了
Seeing you gives me greatjoy.
你能够平安回来 真是太好了
I'm so glad you've come home safely.
跟我来  我们要好好谈谈
Come with me. We have much to talk about.
我不在的时候 你都做了些什么？
I want to hear everything you've been doing.
爸  好多个晚上 我都在做同一个怪梦
Father, for many nights now, I've been having a very strange dream.
我想它是要告诉我 有一些兴奋的事将要发生了
It's telling me something's about to happen, something exciting.
没错 是有些兴奋的事情要发生了
Yes. Something exciting is about to happen.
真的  是什么？
Really? What is it?
高刚已经跟我开口向你提亲了
Kocoum has asked to seek your hand in marriage.
要嫁给高刚？
Marry Kocoum?
我告诉他  我是求之不得
I told him it would make my heart soar.
可是…他好古板哦
But he's so... serious.
乖女儿  高刚会是个好丈夫的
My daughter, Kocoum will make a fine husband.
他为人忠诚  坚强 绝对是个可托付终身的对象
He is loyal and strong and will build you a good house with sturdy walls.
嫁给他  你会很幸福的
With him, you will be safe from harm.
爸  我想我的梦 是在指示我另外一条路
Father, I think my dream is pointing me down another path.
这就是你要走的路啊
This is the right path for you.
我就不能选择吗？
But why can't I choose...
宝嘉康蒂  听我说
Pocahontas, come with me.
你身为酋长的女儿
You are the daughter of the chief.
是时候要建立在族人中的地位
It is time to take your place among our people.
就算是树高千丈 终究要落叶归根
Even the wild mountain stream must someday join the big river.
看着河水流过它
As the river cuts his path
黑夜强风也不怕
Though the river's proud and strong
弯弯曲曲任由它
He will choose the smoothest course
总有一天会到家
That's why rivers live so long.
它坚强
They're steady
不怕风吹和雨打
As the steady beating drum
这项链是你妈妈的嫁妆
Your mother wore this for our wedding.
她老盼望能看你戴着它出嫁
It was her dream to see you wear it at your own.
真配你
It suits you.
他要我稳定下来
He wants me to be steady.
落叶归根
Like the river.
可是我要长流不息
But it's not steady at all.
滚滚的河水是我所爱
What I love most about rivers is
它不停地向两岸拍
You can't step in the same river twice
它日夜不停流过逍遥自在
The water's always changing
它勇往直前  没有终点
Always flowing
努力付出代价
But people, I guess can't live like that
人们不停忙碌
We all must pay a price
可曾仔细想过
To be safe we lose our chance of ever knowing
流水弯弯哪里载
What's around the river bend
看着滚滚流水两岸拍
Waiting just around the river bend
仔细看着
I look once more
滚滚流水两岸拍
Just around the river bend
永不停息
Beyond the shore
看海鸥畅飞
Where the gulls fly free
飞往何方？
Don't know what for
可曾留下仔细看
What I dream the day might send
滚滚流水两岸拍
Just around the river bend
无尽
For me
永无止境
Coming for me
我无时无刻感觉到它 这里就是我的家
I feel it there beyond those trees Or right behind these waterfalls
它不停伴着鼓的敲打声音
Can I ignore that sound of distant drumming?
看那滚滚流水流往何方 你可曾想过
For a handsome, sturdy husband who builds handsome, sturdy walls
它暗示有些事情将会发生
And never dreams that something might be coming
滚滚流水两岸拍
Just around the river bend
流往何处不必猜
不眠不休
I look once more
滚滚流水两岸拍
Just around the river bend
永不停息
Beyond the shore
永远不停息
Somewhere past the sea
心在何方
Don't know what for
我的美梦向天飞
Why do all my dreams extend
滚滚流水两岸拍
Just around the river bend?
Just around the river bend
我该选择些什么
Should I choose the smoothest course
越想越会心事多
Steady as the beating drum?
如果我要嫁给他
Should I marry Kocoum?
一生梦想彷佛不再
Is all my dreaming at an end?
心在彷徨
Or do you still
该往何方看着
Wait for me, dream giver?
滚滚流水
Just around the river
两岸拍
Bend
是不是宝嘉康蒂呀？
Is that my Pocahontas?
柳树婆婆  我有话要跟你说
Grandmother Willow, I need to talk to you.
你早啊  我的孩子
Good morning, child.
我就是盼着你今天能来
I was hoping you'd visit today.
那是你妈妈的项链吧
Why, your mother's necklace!
我就是要来跟你说这个的
That's what I wanted to talk to you about.
我爸爸想要我嫁给高刚
My father wants me to marry Kocoum.
高刚？可是他好古板
Kocoum? But he's so serious!
就是嘛 可是爸爸认为这就是我的路
I know. My father thinks it's the right path for me.
但是…我老做一个梦 这个梦…
But lately, I've been having this dream, and I think it's...
噢  一个梦啊 那就赶快说出来听听啊
Oh, a dream! Let's hear all about it!
别吵
Quiet!
孩子  刚才你在说…
Now, child, you were saying?
我跑着穿过树林
Well, I'm running through the woods,
然后就在我面前有一支箭
and then right there in front of me is an arrow.
当我望向它  它就开始转动
As I look at it, it starts to spin.
一支转动的箭？那多不寻常啊
A spinning arrow? How unusual!
对  它不停地转  越转越快 越转越快  可是突然间  它停了
Yes, it spins faster and faster and faster... until, suddenly, it stops.
看来这转动的箭 似乎是在指引你往下要走的路
Well, it seems to me this spinning arrow is pointing you down your path.
可是柳树婆婆  是什么路啊？
But, Grandmother Willow, what is my path?
我要怎么样才能找到它呢？
How am I ever going to find it?
你妈妈也曾经问过我 同一个问题
Your mother asked me the very same question.
真的？那你怎么说的？
She did? What did you tell her?
我就叫她仔细听
I told her to listen.
在你的周围都是些神灵  孩子
All around you are spirits, child.
生活在土里  流水中  天空上
They live in the earth, the water, the sky.
只要细听就有指引
If you listen, they will guide you.
-我听见风 -对了
- I hear the wind. - Yes.
它在说些什么？
What is it telling you?
我听不太懂
I don't understand.
你会明白
You will understand
用心来聆听
Listen with your heart
心灵的声音
You will understand
让声音轻轻地告诉你人生真谛
Let it break upon you like a wave upon the sand
它在说有些什么要来
It's saying something's coming.
一团怪云？
Strange clouds?
用心来聆听
Listen with your heart
心灵的声音
You will understand
看见什么了？
What do you see?
云彩  一团怪云
Clouds. Strange clouds.
你看  华根 整个新大陆遍布黄金
Look at it, Wiggins, an entire New World chock-full of gold,
在等着我
Just waiting for me.
有更新鲜刺激的事 在等着我们呢  对吗？波斯
And scores of adventures waiting for us, right, Percy?
你说我们会碰上蛮夷吗？
Do you think we'll meet some savages?
真碰上 我们就好好地跟他打个招呼
Ifwe do, we shall be sure to give them a proper English greeting.
见面礼
Gift baskets!
难怪人们喜欢他不喜欢我
And he came so highly recommended.
太理想了  大人  海水深度正好 我们可以直接靠岸了
It's perfect, the water's deep enough. We can pull right up to shore.
嘿  那里  波斯
Hey, there, Percy.
好极了  船立刻靠岸 都安排好了  大人
- Very well, then. Give the order. - Already done, sir.
只等大人下令 随时可以出发了
I've got a crew assembled, and they're ready to go.
那些土著嘛
About the natives...
就看你的 千万别让那些蛮夷
I'm counting on you to make sure those filthy heathens
来坏我们的大事
don't disrupt our mission.
如果他们跟我以前 对付过的蛮夷一样的话
Well, if they're anything like the savages I've fought before,
那绝对没问题
it's nothing I can't handle.
好啊！那就没什么可担心的  迈斯
Right. That'll be all, Smith. There's a good man.
再见  波斯
See ya, Percy.
人们就是喜欢他
The men like Smith, don't they?
可我从来就不受欢迎 你有我呀
- I've never been a popular man. - I like you.
别以为我不知道那些人 在背后是怎么说我的
Don't think I don't know what those backstabbers at court say about me.
噢  对  都说您是个老拼命往上爬
Oh, yes, all that talk about being a pathetic social climber
可是却一事无成的可怜虫 我很清楚
- who's failed at everything... - I'm very well aware that this is
这次是我翻身的机会 你等着瞧  华根
my last chance for glory. But mark my words, Wiggins,
当詹姆国王看到那成堆的黄金
when King James sees the gold these peasants unearth,
这最后的胜利就是我的了
success will be mine, at last.
醒醒！伸个懒腰！ 在桁端的两个！
- Wake up! Shake a leg! - Two of you up on the yardarm!
简直是难以置信
It's incredible.
全都是我们的？ 我从来没见过这么好的地方
And it's all ours. I've never seen anything like it.
其实这个地方 像雷利夫的内裤  我也不在乎
It can look like Ratcliffe's knickers for all I care,
只要能离开这艘烂船
Just as long as I get off this stinking boat!
好了  兄弟们  我们老远地 跑来别站着看
Come on, men. We didn't come all this way just to look at it.
下船吧  伙伴们 用力  用劲  拉紧啊
Keep it taut, lads. Keep it taut! Steady! Steady!
抓牢  抓牢
Hold up! That's far enough!
就这样  绑牢它
All right now... tie her off!
庄哥  抓到这头
Here, John, tie off this end.
庄哥  庄哥？
John? John?
你爬上去干什么啊？ 想看清楚点
- What are you doing up there? - Getting a better look.
嘿！
Hey!
小东西  你样子长得很奇怪
Well... you're a strange looking fellow.
你饿了吗？
You hungry?
拿去吧  这是饼乾
Here you go. It's a biscuit.
食物  对！可以吃的哦
It's food. Well, sort of.
你喜欢啊
You like it, eh?
连吃四个月你就会知道了
Well, try eating it for four months straight.
你伙伴在后头啊
You got a friend back there?
嘿  什么？小心
Hey... what the... What...? Watch out.
别过来  小心！ 庄哥  快点下来！
- No... get that... Look out! - John, you better get down here!
总督大人要上岸了 好了  ！  改天再跟你玩  再见
- The governor's coming ashore. - All right. I'm leaving.
看到他们的皮肤吗？
Did you see their skin?
苍白  带病态
Pale and sickly.
他们脸上有毛  和狗一样
They have hair on their faces like dogs.
兄弟们 要先弄清楚他们的来路
My brothers, we must know more about these visitors.
纪克泰  看到什么了？
Kekata, what do you see?
他们非我族人
These are not men like us...
全是一些受体罚的怪兽
...but strange beasts with bodies that shine like the sun,
携带着会发出雷火的武器
and weapons that spout fire and thunder.
他们像群恶狼四处徘徊
They prowl the earth like ravenous wolves,
不停在寻找捕食的猎物
consuming everything in their path.
包华顿酋长 我这就带着族中勇士沿河道突击
Great Powhatan, I will lead our warriors to the river and attack.
杀他个措手不及 就像打败木索乌美族一样
We will destroy these invaders the way we destroyed the Massawomecks.
高刚  在那场仗中 我们对敌人了若指掌
Kocoum, in that battle we knew how to fight our enemy,
可是我们对这群来客 却一无所知
but these pale visitors are strange to us.
带些人去沿河道监视他们
Take some men to the river to observe them.
希望他们不过是路过而已
Let us hope they do not intend to stay.
我在此宣布 此地一切资源
I hereby claim this land and all its riches
尽归詹姆国王陛下所拥有
in the name of His Majesty, King James the First,
同时将此地命名为詹姆镇
and do so name this settlement Jamestown.
精彩  精彩 大人说得太精彩了
Bravo! Bravo! Beautifully spoken, sir!
快来  波斯
Hurry now, Percy.
快些弄干净见见新大陆了
We must be all squeaky clean for the New World.
庄上尉  看来我选的这个地方 再理想不过了
Captain Smith, it appears I've selected the perfect location.
看不见有蛮夷
Not a savage in sight.
只是我们没看到 不等于他们不存在
Just because we don't see them doesn't mean they're not out there.
也许你该去打探看看 他们究竟躲在何处
Then perhaps you should venture forth and determine their whereabouts.
如果真有蛮夷的话 包在我身上
If there are any Indians out there, I'll find them.
好了  朋友们  开工了
Now, gentlemen, to work.
你们去负责装卸 你们建跑垒
You men, get the ship unloaded, you men build the fort.
剩下的人拿圆锹出来
The rest of you... break out the shovels!
立刻开始挖地 挖地？
- It's time to start digging! - Digging?
当然了  别忘了那些西班牙人
Well, of course! Let's not forget what the Spanish found
在这儿找到了些什么
when they came to the New World.
黄金！  满山都是
Gold! Mountains of it.
多年来  这里的宝贵资源
Why, for years, they've been ravaging the New World
都是任由他们随便取用
of its most precious resources.
但现在…
But now...
轮到我们了
...it's our turn.
科尔特斯的黄金 皮泽洛的珠宝
The gold of Cortéz the jewels of Pizarro
努力不会错 日子将会好过
Will seem like mere trinkets by this time tomorrow
这满地都是
The gold we find here will dwarfthem by far
金光闪闪
Oh, with all you got in ya, boys
像堆火
Dig up Virginia, boys
金色的美梦
Mine, boys
使我很激动
Mine every mountain
一分一秒
And dig, boys
绝不放弃
Dig till ya drop
闭上眼睛渴望
Grab a pick, boys
将来贫穷将离开
Quick, boys
赶快来动起手来  努力开
Shove in a shovel
赶快努力不放弃 财富数之不尽
Uncover those lovely pebbles that sparkle and shine
高人一等 与众不同
It's gold
一切都会属于我
And it's mine, mine, mine
挖  挖  大家一起挖
Dig and diggety dig
And dig and dig and diggety dig
挖  挖  大家一起挖 不怕辛苦
- Hey, nonny, nonny hi, nonny, nonny - Ooh, how I love it
挖  挖  大家一起挖 努力付出
- Hey, nonny, nonny, hi, nonny, nonny - Riches for cheap
挖  挖  大家一起挖 黄金大美梦
- Hey, nonny, nonny, hi, nonny, nonny - There'll be heaps of it
看这富翁多可爱
- And I'll be on top of the heap - Diggety, diggety, diggety, dig!
努力不落空  目标快到达
My rivals back home it's not that I'm bitter
只要努力  总有一天金光散发
But think how they'll squirm when they see how I glitter
明天不一样  不管是真是假
The ladies at court will be all a-twitter
皇上要赏赐我
The king will reward me
称赞我  崇拜我
He'll knight me No! Lord me
是宝藏  张开眼睛就是宝藏
It's mine! Mine, mine for the taking
到处都是  努力挖土
It's mine, boys Mine me that gold
每人都崇拜我  依靠我
With those nuggets dug it's glory they'll give me
拥有尊贵  就要像个国王
My dear friend, King Jimmy will probably build me a shrine
当这一切
When all ofthe gold
都属于我
Is mine
挖  挖  大家努力地挖
And dig and dig and diggety dig
用我一辈子努力 去寻找我梦想
All of my life I have searched for a land like this one
只要努力不放弃 理想终于会实现
A wild or more challenging country I couldn't design
不论再困难 我们提起勇气去面对
Hundreds of dangers await and I don't plan to miss one
踏破千山万水  征服这土地
In a land I can claim, a land I can tame
历经百险  充满刺激 努力不放弃
- The greatest adventure is mine - Keep on working, lads
争取一分钟
- Mine - Don't be shirking, lads
我的金矿
Mine, boys, mine
亮晶晶
Mine me that gold
美丽金矿
- Beautiful gold - Dig for that gold
当美梦来实现
Make this island my land
只要挖到宝不会觉得疲劳
Make the mounds big, boys I'd help you to dig, boys
再也不管腰酸背痛
But I've got this crick in me spine
这地是块宝
- This land we behold - This beauty untold
这话还算早
- A man can be bold - It all can be sold
富贵逼人来
So go for the gold
We know which is here
挖  挖  大家努力地挖
Mine, mine, mine
喂  你等一等  不要跑
No! Wait! Please...
拜托
Please!
你不要走啊
Don't run off.
别怕  我不会伤害你的
It's all right. I'm not going to hurt you.
来  你先上来再说嘛
Here. Let me help you out of there.
我说的话你一句也听不懂吗？
You don't understand a word I'm saying, do you?
来  把手给我
It's all right.
用心来聆听
Listen with your heart
心灵的声音
You will understand
当声音轻轻地告诉你
Let it break upon you
人生真谛
Like a wave upon the sand
你是谁？
Who are you?
用心来聆听
Listen with your heart
心灵的声音
You will understand
宝嘉康蒂
Pocahontas.
什么？你说什么？
What? What did you say?
我的名字叫做宝嘉康蒂
My name is Pocahontas.
我叫庄迈斯
I'm John Smith.
这就对了  就这么挖
That's it. Keep at it, men.
不要停 应该就在这附近
Keep digging. It's got to be here somewhere.
山那边还有三十多个人 加起来超过一百
- There's 30 more down by the ridge. - That makes more than 100!
有了没有？ 没有啊  只有泥巴跟砂石  大人
- Anything yet? - Nothing but rocks and dirt, sir.
我们像这样挖 到底还要挖多久啊？大人
How long are we going to keep digging like this, sir?
当我们是奴隶啊 白天黑夜不停地挖
We're slaving away, busting our backs day and night...
为了国王跟国家
For king and country. I know, I know.
你们辛苦我知道  华根
And I share your fatigue. Wiggins!
华根
Wiggins!
来了 把这扔掉
- Coming! - Dispose of this.
小狗狗乖不乖呀？
Who's a good doggie?
去捡
Fetch, boy!
是蛮夷  大家快拿家伙
Savages! It's an ambush! Arm yourselves!
快逃！
Run!
快拿枪
Arm yourselves!
枪都上膛
Make sure every man has a musket!
开火
Shoot!
向他们射
Them, you idiot!
那该死的庄迈斯 跑哪儿去了？
Where's that blasted Smith when I need him?
罗曼德
Namontack!
撤回部族去
Back to the village!
闭嘴  闭嘴  笨蛋 他们会再来呀
Shut up. Shut up, you fools! They'll be back.
全体撤回营房
Everyone back to camp.
把大跑都移到岸上来 快把跑给弄好
Get the rest of the cannons ashore, finish building the fort!
是  总督大人
Aye, Governor!
你呀 你的枪法该从头学
And you... learn to use that thing properly.
连枪都不会开  算什么男子汉
A man's not a man unless he knows how to shoot.
这些白人是侵略者 真恶毒
These beasts invade our shores, and now this.
这种伤我没见过
This wound is strange to me.
我们要对付敌人 可是绝对不能单独作战
We will fight this enemy, but we cannot do it alone.
高刚  马上派人 将情况通知每个部族
Kocoum, send messengers to every village in our nation.
我们要请他们来共同杀敌
We will call on our brothers to help us fight.
对付白人很危险
These white men are dangerous!
任何人不得接近他们
No one is to go near them.
这个叫头盔
It's called a helmet.
头盔？
Helmet.
这河叫什么？
So... what river is this?
库玉康纳克
Quiyoughcohannock.
你们取的名字真的很奇怪
You have the most unusual names here.
齐克汉密克 库玉…  库玉康纳克
Chickahominy. Quiyo... Quiyoughcohannock.
宝嘉康蒂
Pocahontas.
我觉得你的名字也很奇怪呀
You have the most unusual name, too.
庄迈斯
John Smith.
嘿  这小东西是你朋友吗？
Hey! Is this bottomless pit a friend of yours?
米糕 嗨  你好吗？米糕
- Meeko! - Well, how do you do, Meeko?
别紧张 只是握个手而已呀
It's all right. It's just a handshake.
来呀  我教你
Here, let me show you.
什么都没有啊
Nothing's happening.
当然没有事  把你的手伸给我
No, no. I need your hand first.
我们这是问好
It's how we say hello.
我们是这样子问好的
This is how we say hello. Winggapo.
Winggapo.
这样是说再见
And how we say goodbye. Anah.
我不要跟你说再见
I like hello better.
你少来好不好？
Yeah, I remember you.
菲莉不喜欢陌生人的 我们见过面  不陌生啊
- Flitjust doesn't like strangers. - But I'm not a stranger anymore.
看来他是个小顽固
Stubborn little fellow, isn't he?
非常顽固 嘿！
- Very stubborn. - Hey!
米糕  别乱来呀 不要紧  弄不坏的
- Meeko! Come back here. - Don't worry. He can't hurt it.
嘿！你在干什么？还我 米糕  拿回来
- Hey! What are you doing? - Meeko, bring that back.
算了  没关系  让他留着
No, it's all right. He can keep it.
当是礼物吧
Call it a gift.
那是什么啊？
What was that?
指南针 指南针？
- My compass. - Compass?
你迷路的时候会给你方向
It tells you how to find your way when you get lost.
没关系  我回伦敦可以再买
It's all right. I'll get another in London.
伦敦？是你的部族吗？
London? Is that your village?
对啊  一个很大的部族 什么样子的啊？
- Yes. It's a very big village. - What's it like?
街上到处都是马车
It's got streets filled with carriages,
河上面都是大桥 还有很多很多很高大的楼房
bridges over the rivers, and buildings as tall as trees.
我好想去看看哦 你可以啊
- I'd like to see those things. - You will.
怎么做？ 我们要在这里建一个
- How? - We're going to build them here.
教你们族人 如何运用土地
We'll show your people how to use this land properly.
怎么样去物尽其用 物尽其用？
- How to make the most of it. - Make the most of it?
对呀  开一些路 盖一些很结实的房子
Yes. We'll build roads and decent houses...
我们的房子蛮好的啊
Our houses are fine.
只因为你从来没看过更好的
You think that only because you don't know any better.
你等一等
Wait a minute. Don't take it that...
嘿  等等
Hey! Wait!
怎么了？我们是一番好意
Wait! There's so much we can teach you.
好多蛮夷的生活 都由我们改善了
We've improved the lives of savages all over the world.
蛮夷？
Savages?
蛮夷不是说你
Not that you're a savage.
说我的族人？ 不是
- Just my people. - No.
你先不要误会 我不是这个意思
Listen, that's not what I meant. Let me explain.
让我走 不行  我不能放你走
- Let go! - No. I'm not letting you leave.
你别这样嘛
Look, don't do this.
蛮夷只是一个名词而已 你懂吗？
Savage is just a word, you know?
这是一个统称 那些还没有开发的人
A term for... people who are uncivilized.
像我
Like me.
对  不是  我不是这个意思
Well, when I say uncivilized, what I mean is...
你…你不要误会嘛
What you mean is... not like you.
你的意思是不像你
You think I'm an ignorant savage
尽管你到过很多地方
And you've been so many places
我是可以看得出来 猜得也不会错
I guess it must be so
但是我不明白
But still, I cannot see
怎么想都不明白
Ifthe savage one is me
你聪明 却有很多不知道
How can there be so much that you don't know
不知道
You don't know
别以为 你已占有这块地方
You think you own whatever land you land on
你可曾知道这里有什么
The earth isjust a dead thing you can claim
可知道一块石头  一花一草
But I know every rock and tree and creature
有名字  有着灵气和生命
Has a life, has a spirit, has a name
别一厢情愿以为是人中人
You think the only people who are people
可知道天外还有天更高
Are the people who look and think like you
要尝试跟着别人脚步前往
But if you walk the footsteps of a stranger
慢慢了解很多事情在当中
You'll learn things you never knew you never knew
你会感到黑夜孤单 份外寂寞吗？
Have you ever heard the wolf cry to the blue corn moon?
让春风柔柔轻抚做回答
Or ask the grinning bobcat why he grinned?
就让风声化做歌声围绕山头
Can you sing with all the voices ofthe mountain?
在风中染上色彩化做云烟
Can you paint with all the colors ofthe wind?
在风中染上色彩
Can you paint with all the colors
化做云烟
Ofthe wind?
在走进丛林不会觉得疲倦
Come run the hidden pine trails ofthe forest
来看看这大自然的果园
Come taste the sun-sweet berries ofthe earth
来享受一切丰富阳光资源
Come roll in all the riches all around you
这自然张开双手的怀抱
And for once, never wonder what they're worth
有河川山脉日夜跟我聚首
The rainstorm and the river are my brothers
水獭和飞鸟做我的朋友
The heron and the otter are my friends
但这些都让我们手牵着手
And we are all connected to each other
就在这里找到我们的源头
In a circle, in a hoop, that never ends
你猜树能长多高？
How high does the sycamore grow?
如果砍掉它  永远不知道
If you cut it down then you'll never know
你会感到黑夜孤单 份外寂寞吗？
And you'll never hear the wolf cry to the blue corn moon
让春风柔柔轻抚做回答
For whether we are white or copper-skinned
就让风声化做歌声围绕山头
We need to sing with all the voices ofthe mountain
在风中染上色彩化做云烟
We need to paint with all the colors ofthe wind
你会慢慢发觉到
You can own the earth, and still
你所拥有的一切
All you'll own is earth until
在风中
You can paint
染上色彩
With all the colors
化做
Ofthe
云烟
Wind
是什么啊？
What is it?
鼓声  出麻烦了
The drums. They mean trouble.
我该走了
I shouldn't be here.
什么时候可以再见你？ 不行啊
- I want to see you again. - I can't.
不要  不要走 很抱歉
- Please, don't leave. - I'm sorry.
我得走了
I have to go.
好了  这次差不多了
All right! This one's ready to hoist!
准备好  推
Two on each side. Ready now? Push!
小心点  有点滑
Watch it! It's slipping.
怎么了？伙伴们 一个小事都做不好
Come on, lads, it's only a little picket fence.
拉紧  拉紧 好了
- Steady! Steady! - There you go.
庄哥  这样就什么也进不来了
That'll keep everything out, eh, John?
你怎么了  庄哥？ 什么？
- Something wrong, John? - What?
这几天你总是一句话也不说 他先前没赶上那场热闹
- You've been quiet the last few days. - He's mad he missed all the action.
有什么好担心的  庄哥 一定会有机会让你对付他们
Don't worry, John. You'll get your chance to deal with the Indians.
是啊！到时候我们联手 叫他们吃不了  兜着走
Yeah. We'll take care of them, like we did last time, eh, mates?
来一个我们就杀一个
We shot ourselves an injun
来两个…
Or maybe two or three
别唱了  比杀猪还难听 干活去
All right, you howling nutter, get to work.
拜托！  阿宾  苦中作乐都不行啊
Come on, Ben. It's just a little fun.
说得没错  我们是够苦了
Sure! We're having loads of fun, right?
你看看我们 既没金子  又没得吃
Look at us. No gold, no food,
所有的好处  全让那个死胖子 雷利夫  一个人占尽了
while Ratcliffe sits up in his tent all day, happy as a clam.
怎么搞的？
I'm doomed!
这时候我应该坐拥万金啊 却连金沙都找不到
I should be wallowing in riches by now, and I haven't found as much as a speck.
想一想  想一想 一定就藏在这附近
Think. Think! It's got to be around here somewhere.
究竟在哪？
Where could it be?
我已经把这附近的地方 统统挖过了  都没有
I've mined the forests and the hills and the swamps... and nothing!
怎么会没有？我漏掉了什么？
Why can't I find it? What am I overlooking?
我…我自己做的
I... I... I made it myself!
把它给我拿下来
Take that silly...
对了  印第安鬼
Of course. The Indians.
华根  你说印第安鬼 为什么要来袭击我们？
Wiggins, why do you think those insolent heathens attacked us?
因为我们侵入他们的领土 还有砍树挖地吗？
We invaded their land, cut down their trees and dug up their earth?
是黄金  是他们故意把黄金 藏起来不让我们找到
It's the gold! They have it, and they don't want us to take it from them.
那就只有逼我动用武力去抢
Well, I'll just have to take it by force then, won't I?
你们  庄上尉哪儿去了？
You there! Where's Captain Smith?
他…走了 对  他早就被你吓跑了
- Well, he's... gone. - Aye. Your singing scared him off.
那就找他去  站在这儿干嘛 要是碰到印第安鬼该怎么办？
- Go get him, for heaven's sake! - What ifwe run into the Indians?
难道就不会用你的枪吗？
That's what guns are for.
带上家伙立刻出发
Now arm yourselves and get moving!
宝嘉康蒂
Pocahontas.
你应该留在部族里的
You should be inside the village.
我们正忙着呢
We'll be all right.
勇士们快要到了 我们在准备粮食
We're gathering food for when the warriors arrive.
别走远
Don't go far.
这种时刻可不能再乱跑了 知道了  爸
- Now is not the time to be running off. - Yes, Father.
看你挂上这条项链 就跟你妈一个模样
When I see you wear that necklace, you lookjust like your mother.
我好想她哦
I miss her.
她仍然伴着我们
But she is still with us.
每当风吹过树林 我都感觉得到她的存在
Whenever the wind moves through the trees, I feel her presence.
她是我们族人 智慧和力量的象征
Our people look to her for wisdom and strength.
将来他们要看你的
Someday, they will look to you as well.
我不会让他们失望的
I would be honored by that.
你不该单独在这里
You shouldn't be out here alone.
我叫高刚来 好了  是什么？
- I'll send for Kocoum. - All right, what is it?
什么？ 你心里头有鬼
- What? - You're hiding something.
我哪里有什么鬼呀
I'm not hiding anything.
宝嘉康蒂  你告诉我  我保证
Pocahontas, you can tell me. I promise.
我绝对不会告诉别人的 宝嘉康蒂  你看
I won't tell anyone... Pocahontas, look!
是个白人！我要去通知… 你来这儿干什么？
- It's one of them! I'm going to get... - What are you doing here?
我要来看你呀
I had to see you again.
宝嘉康蒂  宝嘉康蒂 拜托  你什么都别说
- Pocahontas! Pocahontas! - Please! Don't say anything.
快！跟我来！
Quick! This way!
可是… 尼可曼
- But... - Nakoma.
宝嘉康蒂人呢？ 我…我没看见她
- Where is Pocahontas? - I haven't seen her.
她不能老是到处乱跑 这样子是非常危险的
Pocahontas can't keep running off. It's dangerous out there.
劝劝她  她都听你的
Tell her that. She listens to you.
哼  她才不呢
Sure she does.
真是世外桃源
This place is incredible.
可是我们那班人 只是想着来挖黄金
And to think we came all this way Just to dig it up for gold.
黄金？ 嗨  米糕
- Gold? - Hey, Meeko.
什么黄金啊？ 黄金就是黄黄的
- What's gold? - You know, it's yellow.
从地下出来  很值钱的
It comes out of the ground. It's really valuable.
在这儿  我们有好多哦
Here, we have lots of it.
黄金
Gold.
不是这个  这个才是  黄金
No, no! Gold is this.
这里没有这种东西
There's nothing like that around here.
没有？ 我没见过
- No gold? - Not that I've seen.
如果他们知道
All this way for nothing.
这里没有黄金的话 一定很失望
Those boys are in for a big surprise.
他们会走吗？ 有些会吧
- Will they leave? - Some of them might.
你也回家？
Will you go home?
我一向是到处流浪  四海为家
Well, it's not like I have much of a home to go back to.
回不回去也无所谓
I've never really belonged anywhere.
那你留下来
You could belong here.
这是什么？
What was that?
你看见什么了？ 没有  没有  我只是…
- Did you see something? - No, no. I just...
我真的没有看到东西 怎么了？
I didn't see anything. Did I?
再看哪
Look again.
让声音轻轻地告诉你
Let it break upon you
人生真谛
Like a wave upon the sand
你好  庄迈斯
Hello, John Smith.
宝嘉康蒂  树在跟我说话？
Pocahontas, that tree is talking to me.
那你快回话啊
Then you should talk back.
不要怕呀  小伙子
Don't be frightened, young man.
我可不会咬人的
My bark is worse than my bite.
说话呀 跟树要说什么？
- Say something. - What do you say to a tree?
什么都可以
Anything you want.
好啊  你好 走过来  庄迈斯
- So... - Come closer, John Smith.
他心肠挺好的  长得好帅呀
He has a good soul. And he's handsome, too!
我喜欢她 我知道你会
- Oh, I like her. - I knew you would.
迈斯  迈斯  你在哪儿啊？
Smith! Smith, where are you, mate?
不要让他们看到 快  到这儿来
- We can't let them see us. - Quick! Over here.
这个地方好吓人啊 那些蛮夷可能就躲在附近
This place gives me the creeps. Savages could be hiding anywhere.
怕什么 让我看见  二话不说开枪
If you spot one, don't ask questions. Just shoot.
你干什么绊我啊？ 不是我  是那棵树
- Watch your feet, you big oaf! - It wasn't me! It was the tree.
是啊  是那棵树抬起脚 把我给绊倒的
Of course! The tree just felt like lifting its roots...
我们快离开这儿吧
Let's get out of here.
快跑 那庄迈斯怎么办呢？
- Run! - But what about Smith?
别管他了  他会照顾自己的
He's a big lad, he can take care of himself!
还好没有跟你作对
I'm glad you're on our side.
这几条老筋还挺管用的呢
There's still some snap in these old vines.
我先回去了 不然他们会全部出来找我
I better get back before they send the whole camp after me.
什么时候再见啊？ 今天晚上  在这儿
- When will I see you again? - Meet me tonight, right here.
哇  这两百年来 都没碰过这么兴奋的事情
Well! I haven't had this much excitement in 200 years.
我是怎么了？ 我不应该再跟他见面的
What am I doing? I shouldn't be seeing him again.
可是我实在想见到他
I mean, I want to see him again.
就是嘛！我也想再见到他
Who wouldn't? I want to see him again.
我觉得好像 有些什么在告诉我  这是对的
But, still, something inside is telling me it's the right thing.
也许是你的梦
Perhaps it's your dream.
我的梦？柳树婆婆  你说那支箭 所指的会不会就是他？
My dream? Do you think he's the one the spinning arrow was pointing to?
勇士们来了
The warriors are here.
宝嘉康蒂  你疯了 跟那个白人混在一起
Pocahontas, are you crazy? What were you doing with one of them?
你在这儿 高刚
- There you are! - Kocoum!
你看看  现在人强马壮 一定能把白鬼赶尽杀绝
Look at them! Now we have enough warriors to destroy those white demons!
团结起各部族的力量 我们一定能打败敌人
Now that we are joined by our brothers, we will defeat this enemy.
爸  我有话要跟你说
Father, I need to speak with you.
现在不行  乖女儿 联盟正在集会
Not now, my daughter. The council is gathering.
不一定非要开战啊 一定有更好的方法
We don't have to fight them. There must be a better way.
这个时候 已经由不得我们选择了
Sometimes our paths are chosen for us.
也许你该去跟他们谈一谈
But maybe we should try talking to them.
他们不会想谈的
They do not want to talk.
如果他们真的愿意谈呢？ 你会听他们说吗？你会吗？
But if one of them did want to talk, you would listen to him, wouldn't you?
宝嘉康蒂 你会吗？
- Pocahontas... - Wouldn't you?
我当然会了 但怎么会那么简单
Of course I would, but it is not that simple.
事情已经不再单纯了
Nothing is simple anymore.
慢着  汤姆斯  是我
Easy, Thomas, it's me.
庄哥  我差点就开枪了 你根本没有瞄准目标
- Oh, John! I could've killed you. - Not aiming like that, you couldn't.
开枪的时候两眼睁开 才看得更清楚
Keep both eyes open when you shoot. You'll see twice as well.
迈斯  回来了 我们一直在到处找你
- Smith! There you are. - We were looking all over for you.
迈斯  你跑哪儿去了？
Smith! Where have you been?
大人  我到周围查看一下而已
I was out scouting the terrain, sir.
很好  那你一定 对印第安鬼了若指掌了
Excellent. Then you must know the Indians' whereabouts.
要开战就该知己知彼
We'll need that information for the battle.
开战？ 我们一定要把这些蛮夷
- What battle? - We will eliminate these savages
赶尽杀绝 不行  你不能这样做
- once and for all. - No! You can't do that!
噢  不能？ 对  我们用不着打他们
- Oh, can't I? - Look. We don't have to fight them.
庄哥  这什么意思？ 我遇上他们
- John, what's gotten into you? - I met one of them.
什么？ 遇上蛮夷了？
- You what? - A savage?
他们不是蛮夷  他们能帮助我们
They're not savages. They can help us.
他们熟悉土地 懂得如何测定河道
They know the land. They know how to navigate the rivers.
你看  是粮食 这是什么东西？
- And look. It's food. - What is it?
比饼乾跟燕麦粥好吃多了
It's better than hardtack and gruel, that's for sure.
燕麦粥好
I like gruel.
他们才不会要请客吃饭
They don't want to feed us, you ninnies!
他们要杀人  杀我们
They want to kill us! All of us!
为了独霸黄金 他们用上好多诡计
They've got our gold, and they'll do anything to keep it!
这里根本就没有黄金 没有黄金？
- But there is no gold. - No gold?
我看是你的那位 印第安朋友告诉你的吧？
And I suppose your little Indian friend told you this?
是的
Yes.
撒谎  撒谎  全都撒谎 凶险的小偷
Lies. Lies! All of it! Murderous thieves.
我们文明社会 不容许这种贼存在
There's no room for their kind in civilized society.
可是这里是他们的土地！
But this is their land!
这里是我的  我就是法律
This is my land! I make the laws here.
听清楚  要是任何一个人 见到印第安鬼
And I say anyone who so much as looks at an Indian
而不杀他的话 就等于是造反  要问罪
without killing him on sight will be tried for treason and hanged.
宝嘉康蒂
Pocahontas!
尼可曼 不要再去了
- Nakoma. - Don't go out there.
我已经为你撒过谎 你不能一错再错啊
I lied for you once, don't ask me to do it again.
我一定要去
I have to do this.
他是白人 你不了解
- He's one of them! - You don't know him.
你去见他 就等于背叛自己的族人
If you go out there, you'll be turning your back on your own people.
我这么做是要帮助我的族人
I'm trying to help my people.
宝嘉康蒂  不要去 你是我的好朋友
Pocahontas, please, you're my best friend.
我不要你受到伤害
I don't want you to get hurt.
放心  我不会有事的 宝嘉康蒂  不要！
- I won't. I know what I'm doing. - Pocahontas, no!
雷利夫 不会真叫我们空手而回吧
Ratcliffe wouldn't take us halfway around the world for nothing.
如果迈斯是对的 如果这里真的是没有黄金
But what if Smith is right? What if there is no gold?
你是说雷利夫一直在欺骗我们
If you ask me, Ratcliffe's been lying to us since we left London.
瞧你说的  你们这群笨蛋
Listen to you, you bunch of idiots.
如果什么都没有 那些蛮夷才不会攻击我们
Those savages didn't attack us for nothing.
他们一定藏着一些东西
They're hiding something.
要是真的有黄金 我们就得跟他们拼命了
If they do have the gold, I reckon we'll have to fight them.
我不会  我才不会冒着危险… 不是太热就是太冷
- Not me. I'm not risking my neck... - Either too hot or too cold.
自从来了这里 我就一直感到不安
I haven't been comfortable since we got here.
我也觉得浑身不自在
Me, too. I'm itching a lot.
跟踪他 是  总督大人
- Follow him. - Yes, Governor.
我要知道他究竟去哪里？
I want to know where he's sneaking off to.
是  大人 如果遇见印第安鬼
- Yes, sir. - If you happen to see any Indians...
就开枪
...shoot them.
还有  汤姆斯 你无论当水手
And, Thomas, you've been a slipshod sailor
和军人的表现都不怎么样
and a poor excuse for a soldier.
别再叫我失望了
Don't disappoint me again.
高刚 什么事？
- Kocoum. - What is it?
宝嘉康蒂她… 怎么了？她怎么了？
- It's Pocahontas. - What's wrong? Is she all right?
我想她遇上了麻烦
I think she's in trouble.
大地在发抖啊  孩子 出了什么事了？
The earth is trembling, child. What's happened?
勇士们都来了
The warriors are here.
宝嘉康蒂 迈斯
- Pocahontas. - John!
你听我说 我们的人正准备攻打你们
Listen to me. My men are planning to attack your people.
你们一定要小心
You've got to warn them.
也许现在还来得及阻止他
Maybe it's not too late to stop this.
你得要跟我去和我爸爸谈一谈
You have to come with me and talk to my father.
宝嘉康蒂 我看谈也是于事无补的
Pocahontas, talking isn't going to do any good.
我已经跟我的人谈过了
I already tried talking to my men,
他们简直就是无药可救
but everything about this land has them spooked.
我从来没有见过那样的怪物
That's the strangest creature I've ever seen!
波斯？
Percy?
放松  波斯！过来 米糕  回来
- Easy, Percy! Come here! - Meeko, come back!
你都看到了  两边如果拼上了 怎么能挡得住呢？
You see what I mean? Once two sides want to fight, nothing can stop them.
好了  你们两个 没事  他是朋友
- Come here, both of you! - It's all right. He's a friend.
坏坏狗  给我坐下
Bad! Bad dog! Sit!
米糕  你在干什么？ 波斯  不要再闹了
- What are you doing? Meeko! - Percy, get back here!
你在干什么？停啊 够了  我受够了
- What are you doing? Stop that! - All right, that's enough!
这就够让你们筋疲力尽了
It's enough to make your sap boil.
现在我要让你们看些东西  看啊
Now then, there's something I want to show you. Look!
是涟漪 什么意思？
- The ripples. - What about them?
开始小小的  然后越来越大
So small at first, then look how they grow.
可得要有人先开始哦
But someone has to start them.
他们是不会听我们的了
They're not going to listen to us.
小伙子 正确的路都是不容易走的
Young man, sometimes the right path is not the easiest one.
知道吗？
Don't you see?
你们要在一起 就一定要他们停战
Only when the fighting stops can you be together.
好吧  我们去见你爸爸
All right. Let's go talk to your father.
高刚  不要！
Kocoum, no!
高刚
Kocoum!
你放开他
Leave him alone!
高刚  住手
Kocoum, stop!
两眼睁开
Both eyes open.
汤姆斯 中了…
- Thomas! - Is he...
你杀了他
You killed him.
我以为… 走开  你走开
- I thought that... - Get away from him!
宝嘉康蒂  不要 他只是想…
Pocahontas, it won't help! He was only...
他杀了他
He killed him!
Get all the wagons...
汤姆斯  快点离开 快点走啊
Thomas, get out of here! Get out of here!
是谁干的？
Who did this?
宝嘉康蒂跑到树林里
Pocahontas was out in the woods.
高刚跟去找她 这个白人袭击他
Kocoum went to find her and this white man attacked them.
你的武器很厉害 可是敌不上我们的愤怒
Your weapons are strong, but now our anger is stronger.
到日出时刻  第一个先处决他 可是爸…
- At sunrise, he'll be the first to die! - But Father!
我叫你留在部族里头
I told you to stay in the village.
你就是不听
You disobeyed me.
你让你爸爸丢脸 我只是想要帮助大家
- You have shamed your father! - I was only trying to help.
就因为你的无知 高刚牺牲了
Because of your foolishness, Kocoum is dead!
把他带走
Take him away!
高刚全是为了要保护我
Kocoum was just coming to protect me.
宝嘉康蒂 是我要高刚去的
Pocahontas... I sent Kocoum after you.
我实在很担心你
I was worried about you.
我以为我这样做是对的
I thought I was doing the right thing.
所有的事都因我而起
All this happened because of me.
我再也不能够见到庄迈斯了
And now I'll never see John Smith again.
跟我来
Come with me.
宝嘉康蒂她想要亲自审问 那个杀掉高刚的人
Pocahontas wants to look into the eyes of the man who killed Kocoum.
要快点
Be quick.
宝嘉康蒂
Pocahontas.
我很抱歉 为什么？这个啊？
- I'm so sorry. - For what? This?
我受过比这个还重的伤
I've gotten out of worse scrapes than this.
现在可想不起来
Can't think of any right now, but...
如果我们从没遇到过多好
It would've been better ifwe'd never met.
什么都不会发生了 宝嘉康蒂  你看着我
- None of this would've happened. - Pocahontas, look at me.
我情愿明天死掉 也不要长命百岁而不认识你
I'd rather die tomorrow than live a hundred years without knowing you.
宝嘉康蒂 我不能没有你
- Pocahontas. - I can't leave you.
绝对不会
You never will.
无论我发生什么事 我都与你同在  直到永远
No matter what happens to me, I'll always be with you. Forever.
快呀  大家快来呀
Help! Somebody help! Help!
快呀 你别急呀  兄弟  有什么事啊？
- Help! - Easy, lad. What is it?
是庄迈斯  他被抓了
It's Smith! They got him!
被谁抓了？ 蛮夷！
- Who got him? - The savages!
蛮夷？ 把他绑起来  带走了
- Savages? - They captured him! Dragged him off!
往哪儿去了？ 往北边去了
- Where'd they take him? - They headed north.
有多少人啊？ 不清楚  起码十几个
- How many were there? - I don't know. At least a dozen.
肮脏的野兽！
Filthy beasts!
这当然是对的  华根 我这是得来全不费功夫
It's perfect, Wiggins! I couldn't have planned this better myself.
黄金全是我的了
The gold is as good as mine.
把他救回来 不能丢下他不管啊
We've got to save him! He'd do the same for any of us.
他说得对  我们一定要去救他
Thomas is right! We've got to do something.
那当然了  我早就说 蛮夷是绝对不可以相信的
And so we shall. I told you those savages couldn't be trusted.
庄迈斯相信他们 他们是怎么对他的？
Smith tried to befriend them, and look what they've done to him!
我们一定要尽全力 把我们的好兄弟救回来
But now I say it's time to rescue our courageous comrade.
天一亮  我们就出击！
At daybreak, we attack!
你怎么会知道 会遇到这一群人？
What can you expect from filthy little heathens?
全都是令人恶心的家伙
Here's what you get when races are diverse
看他们的颜色
Their skin's a hellish red
像火一般炽热
They're only good when dead
是邪恶魔鬼的化身
They're vermin as I said and worse
是野蛮人  野蛮人
They're savages, savages
野蛮不讲道理 野蛮人  野蛮人
- Barely even human - Savages, savages
把他赶走吧
Drive them from our shore!
他们不像我们
They're not like you and me
野蛮又不讲道理
Which means they must be evil
我们要提高警惕
We must sound the drums ofwar
是野蛮人  野蛮人
They're savages, savages
野蛮不讲道理
Dirty, shrieking devils
我们用心来对抗
Now we sound the drums ofwar
你可曾知道
This is what we feared
贪得无厌的欲望
The paleface is a demon
是他们与生俱来的本性
The only thing they feel at all is greed
外表虽然好看
Beneath that milky hide
其实邪恶丑陋
There's emptiness inside
他们无理又像野兽
I wonder ifthey even bleed
是野蛮人  野蛮人
They're savages, savages
野蛮不讲道理
Barely even human
野蛮人  野蛮人
Savages, savages
要小心提防
Killers at the core
用尽一切方法
They're different from us
把他赶出这地方
Which means they can't be trusted
绝不会让他好过
We must sound the drums ofwar
是野蛮人  野蛮人
They're savages, savages
野蛮不讲道理
First we deal with this one
让我们点燃战火
Then we sound the drums ofwar
野蛮人  野蛮人
Savages, savages
杀他个片甲不留
Let's go get a few, men!
野蛮人  野蛮人
Savages, savages
一个也不漏
Now it's up to you, men!
野蛮人 野蛮人
- Savages - Savages
我们毫不害怕
Barely even human
让我们
Now we sound the drums
跟他们战斗
Ofwar
柳树婆婆  太阳出来 他们就要杀掉他了
They're going to kill him at sunrise, Grandmother Willow.
你一定要阻止他们
You have to stop them.
我不行 孩子  记住你的梦吗？
- I can't. - Child, remember your dream.
我是错的  柳树婆婆 我是走错了路
I was wrong, Grandmother Willow. I followed the wrong path.
我该怎么办呢？
I feel so lost.
指南针
The compass.
会转动的箭
The spinning arrow.
他就是你梦中的箭啊
It's the arrow from your dream!
没错  箭头就是指向他
I was right. It was pointing to him!
日出 现在还不太迟  孩子！
- Sunrise. - It's not too late, child!
让大地的神灵给你指引
Let the spirits of the earth guide you!
让你知道该走的路 孩子  走下去
You know your path, child. Now follow it!
今天要发威
This will be the day
勇往直前
Let's go, men!
看谁也不怕谁
This will be the morning
把犯人带出来
Bring out the prisoner!
我要他们战死在沙场
We will see them dying in the dust
不知我能做什么？
I don't know what I can do
多我一个不嫌多
Still I know I've got to try
叫他把命赔
Now we make them pay
正义站在我这方
Eagle, help my feet to fly
谁也不怕谁
Now, without a warning
一定会平安渡过
Mountain, help my heart be great
多少英雄战死在沙场
Now we leave them blood and bone and rust
回家大门为我开 多少  牺牲
- Spirits ofthe earth and sky - It's them or us
打铁趁热要赶快
Please don't let it be too late
肮脏的野蛮人
They're a bunch of filthy, stinking savages
野蛮人 白鬼
- Savages - Demons
恶魔 杀吧
- Devils - Kill them!
野蛮人 野蛮人
- Savages - Savages
你们在等什么？
What are we waiting for?
作战不眠不休 来杀个片甲不留
Destroy their evil race until there's not a trace left
谁来点起这战火
How loud are the drums ofwar?
看谁最勇敢
Now we see what comes oftrying to be chums
不畏缩  不害怕 快快来迎接
Is the death of all I love carried in the drumming of
这战火 不  ！
- War - No!
如果你要杀他 得把我一起杀掉
If you kill him, you'll have to kill me too.
女儿  退下去
Daughter, stand back.
我不要  爸  我爱他
I won't! I love him, Father.
你自己看看
Look around you.
是仇恨带我们走上这条路的
This is where the path of hatred has brought us.
我选择了自己的路  爸
This is the path I choose, Father.
你会怎么选呢？
What will yours be?
我女儿说的话 超越她年龄的智慧
My daughter speaks with a wisdom beyond her years.
我们内心都带着愤怒而来
We have all come here with anger in our hearts,
而她所带着的是勇气和谅解
but she comes with courage and understanding.
从今天开始 如果再有杀戮的事情
From this day forward, if there is to be more killing,
一切都与我无关
it will not start with me.
放了他
Release him.
是时候了  开火
Now is our chance! Fire!
不 什么？
- No. - What?
他们已经放人了 他们不想打了
- They let him go! - They don't want to fight!
这是诡计  知道吗？开火！
It's a trick, don't you see? Fire!
开火  好  我亲自出马
Fine! I'll settle this myself.
不要
No!
庄哥
John!
你射他
You shot him!
是他自己跑过去的 是他不对呀
He stepped right into it! It's his own fault!
庄迈斯一直都是对的 我们根本就不该听你的
- Smith was right all along. - We never should've listened to you.
拿起枪！ 造反了  ！
- Get the gun! - Traitors!
放开我  你们胆大包天！
Unhand me, I say. How dare you!
把他铐起来！
Put him in chains!
我会拿你们问罪
I'll see you all hanged for this!
把他的嘴堵住
And gag him as well!
他熬得过去吗  汤姆斯？
Is he going to make it, Thomas?
最好赶快把送他回伦敦
The sooner he gets to England, the better.
但愿一切平安顺利
Let's hope the wind is with him.
船准备好了吗？ 随时都能启航
- Is the ship ready yet? - Any minute now.
现在就等最后几件货装上去
Just loading the last bit of cargo.
放开我 你们不怕杀头啊？
Untie me at once! I'll have your head for this!
人们总是对他推崇备至
And he came so highly recommended.
船随时能启航
The ship's almost ready.
得先把你抬上船 要赶上涨潮
We'd better get you on board. We'll lose the tide.
不要  等一等 她说她会来的
No, not yet. She said she'd be here.
来了
Look.
回伦敦是他唯一的机会
Going back is his only chance.
要不然他的命就保不住了
He'll die if he stays here.
给
Here.
这是柳树婆婆树上的树皮
It's from Grandmother Willow's bark.
能减轻痛苦
It'll help with the pain.
什么痛苦？ 还有比这个更痛的
What pain? I've had worse pain than this.
只要看到你就好了
Can't think of any right now, but...
我跟我的族人永远欢迎你
You are always welcome among our people.
谢谢  好兄弟
Thank you, my brother.
我以为你抗拒外人
I thought you didn't like strangers.
我妈的项链
My mother's necklace.
谢谢了  波斯
See ya, Percy.
跟我走吧
Come with me?
你要选定你自己的路
You must choose your own path.
这里需要我
I'm needed here.
那…我陪你留下来
Then... I'll stay with you.
不  你得要回去
No. You have to go back.
我离不开你 你放心吧
- But I can't leave you. - You never will.
无论发生什么事 我都与你同在
No matter what happens, I'll always be with you...
直到永远
...forever.
保重了  迈斯 顺风  庄哥
- Good luck, lad. - Godspeed, John.
一切就位了吗？ 是  大人
- The crew a-ready? - Aye, sir!
起航…
Set the mainsails.
起锚
Weigh anchor!
大家起航
Let go of the topgallants!
谢谢观赏